gurock.com 2019-03-13

# Gurock Software's Privacy Policy

## Last Updated: May 3, 2018

Gurock Software GmbH ("Gurock") is committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of our customers, partners, webinars attendees and website visitors. Specifically, we do not sell, rent or trade email lists with other companies for marketing purposes. In this Privacy Statement we describe Gurock's privacy practices in relation to the use of Gurock Website (as defined below) and the related applications, services, products and programs offered by Gurock (collectively, "Services"), as well as individuals’ choices regarding use, access and correction of personal information.

If you have questions or complaints regarding Gurock’s Privacy Statement or associated practices, please contact us at [compliance@gurock.io](mailto:%20compliance@gurock.io).

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices, including how Gurock collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide to its website (the "Gurock Website").

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify you, such as, your name, title, phone number, email address, or mailing address.

In general, you can browse our website without giving us any personal information. We use web analytics software to analyze traffic to this web site in order to understand our customer's and visitor's needs and to continually improve our site for them. This software collects only anonymous, aggregate statistics. For example, we do not tie a specific visit to a specific IP address.

If you want to subscribe to a periodic communication such as a newsletter, we ask you to simply provide your business email address ("Optional Information"). Additional activities on our site may require you to be registered, for example, to read a white paper, download trial or free software, when you express an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services or register for an event. As part of the registration process, we may ask you for additional personal information, such as name, Gurock name, address, phone number, and email address (“Required Information”). We use that information for several general purposes: to tell you about products and services if you so request, to fulfill your request, to contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information; to verify the accuracy of our records, to contact you regarding customer satisfaction surveys. 

For our downloadable software products, as part of the Required Information, on installation and execution, some of our products may send Gurock certain information, including product version, product edition, and information about the operation system and/or environment where the product is installed. Solely for our software as a service products, as part of the Required Information and in order to provide the Services to you, we store all the content you provide, including but not limited to accounts created for team members, files, pictures, project information, and any other information that you provide to the Services you use. Even though Gurock stores these data as part of its Services to you, Gurock does not have access or collect such data. We may also collect data about usage of the software. This may include, but is not limited to, numbers of users and groups, frequency and size of attachments, actions invoked in the product, IP addresses used to access the service, operating environment, and other interactions with product features. This information may be analyzed for security and auditing purposes.

When purchasing Services or registering for an event, Gurock may also require you to provide your billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number (“Billing Information”). Some activities require additional personal information. For example, to fulfill online orders for products, we require you to enter credit card information, and you have the option to provide a separate shipping address. When visitors of Gurock Website apply for a job with Gurock, Gurock may also require you to submit additional personal information as well as a resume or curriculum vitae (“Applicant Information”). Gurock may check for license validation and software updates for some of its products. Required Information, Optional Information, Billing Information, Applicant Information and any other information you submit to the Gurock through the Services or information provided to you by the Gurock through your use of the Services (e.g. license key) are referred to collectively as “Data.”

As you navigate Gurock Website, Gurock may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons. Website Navigational Information as defined in Section 7 below, includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on Idera’s web pages viewed and the links clicked). For additional information about the collection of Website Navigational Information by Idera and others, please see Section 7 below.

Gurock uses Data about Gurock’s customers to perform the Services requested. For example, if you fill out a “Try TestRail for free” Web form, Gurock will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Services. In addition, the Gurock may use Data where it believes, in our sole judgment, to protect our rights and interests, for example to check for license validation either using the license key or your account details. Some software products can also use license information to inform you of the availability of applicable updates.

Gurock also uses Data about webinars attendees to plan and host corporate events, host online forums and social networks in which event attendees may participate, and to populate online profiles for webinars attendees on Gurock Website. Additional information on Gurock’s privacy practices with respect to Data about webinars attendees may be found in additional privacy statements on the event Websites, as the case may be.

Gurock may also use Data about customers and webinar attendees for marketing purposes. For example, Gurock may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in the Services and to send you information regarding Gurock, its affiliates, and its partners, such as information about promotions or events.

Gurock may also receive information about customers and attendees from other sources, including third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this information with Data we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and create more tailored advertising to provide products and services that may be of interest to you.

Gurock uses credit card information solely to collect payment from prospective customers and attendees.

Gurock uses Website Navigational Information to operate and improve Gurock Website. Gurock may also use Website Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data about customers and Data about webinar attendees to provide personalized information about Gurock. For additional information about the use of Website Navigational Information, please see the Section 7 below.

## Business Partners.

From time to time, Gurock may partner with other companies to jointly offer products, services or programs (such as webinars or downloadable content) such as our channel partners to fulfill product trials and information requests, and provide customers and prospective customers with information about Gurock and its products. To do this, we may pass your information to them for that purpose only, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. Gurock does not share Data about the Gurock attendees with business partners unless: (1) you specifically opt in to such sharing via an event registration form; or (2) you attend a Gurock event and allow the Gurock or any of its business partners to scan your attendee badge. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may choose not to opt in via event registration forms and elect not to have your badge scanned at Gurock events.  If you choose to share your information with business partners in the manners described above, your information will be subject to the business partners’ respective privacy statements.

Gurock sometimes hires vendor companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering items, sending postal mail, providing technical support, and processing event registrations. We provide those companies only the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

## Third Parties.

Section 7 of this Privacy Statement, Website Navigational Information, specifically addresses the information we or third parties collect through cookies and web beacons, and how you can control cookies through your Web browser. We may also disclose your personal information to any third party with your prior consent.

## Service Providers.

Gurock may share Data about Gurock website visitors, customers and webinar attendees with Gurock’s contracted service providers so that these service providers can provide services on our behalf. These service providers are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide the requested services to us.  Without limiting the foregoing, Gurock may also share Data about Gurock website visitors, customers and webinar attendees with Gurock’s service providers to ensure the quality of information provided, and with third–party social networking and media websites, such as Facebook, for marketing and advertising on those websites. Unless described in this Privacy Statement, Gurock does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

## Billing.

Gurock uses a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on Gurock’s behalf.

## Gurock Affiliates.

Gurock may share Data about the Gurock’s customers with other companies in order to work with them, including affiliates of the Gurock corporate group. For example, Gurock may need to share Data about Gurock customers with other companies within the Gurock corporate family for customer support, marketing, technical operations and account management purposes. The data protection laws in these countries may be more or less extensive than laws in the country in which you are located. However, Gurock and its offices and affiliates are governed by this Privacy Statement and will use your personal information only as set forth in this Privacy Statement.

## Compelled Disclosure.

Gurock may also disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange or other disposition (whether of assets, stock or otherwise) of all or a portion of a business of Gurock and/or its subsidiaries or to (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process served on Gurock or this website; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Gurock and this website; (3) enforce its agreements with you, or (4) act in urgent circumstances to protect personal safety or the public. 

Gurock Website does not offer information intended to attract children. Gurock does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 16.

When you submit any form requiring registration, we use a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) helps protect your information as it travels over the Internet by encrypting that information before it is sent to us. We have also implemented industry-standard security mechanisms and procedures to protect data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

## Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Addresses.

Gurock uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons, to collect information as you navigate Gurock Website (“Website Navigational Information”). As described more fully below, we and our partners use these cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer Websites and Services, track users’ movements around our Websites and Services, serve targeted advertisements and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.  This section describes the types of Website Navigational Information used on Gurock Website and Services, and how this information may be used.

## Log Files, IP Addresses, URLs and Other Data.

As is true of Gurock Website, we gather certain information automatically to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer Gurock Website and Services.  This information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), device and application identification numbers, your location, your browser type, your Internet service provider and/or mobile carrier, the pages and files you viewed, your searches, your operating system and system configuration information, and date/time stamps associated with your usage. Due to Internet communications standards, when you visit or use Gurock Website and Services, we automatically receive the URL of the website from which you came and the website to which you go when you leave our Website. This information is used to analyze overall trends, to help us improve our Websites and Services, to track and aggregate non-personal information, and to provide the Websites and Services. For example, Gurock uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which customers and website visitors navigate the Gurock Website. Gurock also collects IP addresses from customers when they log into the Services as part of Gurock’s “Identity Confirmation” and “IP Range Restrictions” security features.

## Cookies

Gurock uses cookies to make interactions with Gurock Website easy and meaningful. When you visit Gurock Website, Gurock’s servers send a cookie to your computer or device. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you; they merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to Gurock, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a Web form (such as a “Request a Demo” or a “Request a Quote” Web form) or have previously identified yourself to Gurock, you remain anonymous to Gurock.

Gurock uses cookies that are session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer or device when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer or device after you close your browser or turn off your computer. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on Gurock Website or Services.

The following sets out how Gurock uses different categories of cookies.

## Required Cookies: 

Required cookies enable you to navigate Gurock Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website and using Gurock Services. If you have chosen to identify yourself to Gurock, Gurock may place on your browser cookies containing an encrypted, unique identifier. These cookies allow Gurock to uniquely identify you when you are logged into Gurock Website and Services and to process your online transactions and requests. 

## Functionality Cookies: 

Functionality cookies allow Gurock Website and Services to remember information you have entered or choices you make (such as your username, language, or your region) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of Gurock Website and Services after logging in. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize.

Functional cookies may also be used to improve how Gurock Website and Services function and perform, to enhance and customize your interactions with Gurock, and to help us provide you with more relevant messages, including marketing communications. These cookies collect information about how website visitors use our Website and Services, including which pages visitors go to most often and if they receive error messages from certain pages.

Gurock may use its own technology (under Gurock brand name or an affiliated brand name) or third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from website visitors, attendees, and customers, to provide enhanced interactions and more relevant communications, and to track the performance of Gurock's advertisements. Gurock and its third-party partners may also utilize HTML5 local storage or Flash cookies for these purposes. Flash cookies and HTML local storage are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Gurock also uses Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on Gurock Website and Services to personalize your visit. 

## Targeting or Advertising Cookies: 

Gurock sometimes uses cookies delivered by third parties to show you ads for Gurock products and services that we think may interest you on any devices you may use and to track the performance of Gurock advertisements.  For example, in these cases, cookies remember information such as which browsers have visited Gurock Website. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after Gurock receives it. If Gurock is using one of its own cookie-related products on our own Website, then a cookie related to ads may appear on our Website under Gurock or one of our affiliated Gurock's name.

Gurock also contracts with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from Web beacons (see below) on Gurock Website and Services, from emails, and on third-party websites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time and across different sites or other online services by collecting Website Navigational Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. These technologies may recognize you across the different devices you use, such as a desktop or laptop computer, smartphone or tablet. Third parties use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other websites or mobile applications on any of your devices. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Third parties, with whom Gurock partners to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.  Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.

## Do Not Track. 

Currently, various browsers — including Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari — offer a "do not track" or "DNT" option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal to websites’ visited by the user about the user's browser DNT preference setting. Gurock does not currently commit to responding to browsers' DNT signals with respect to Gurock Website, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent. Gurock takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard.

Our Website contain links to information on other websites. We do not have any control over these other websites, and therefore we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting those websites. Those websites are not governed by this Privacy Statement, and if you have questions about how a website uses your information, consult that website's privacy statement. Portions of this website may also make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to visitors. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information. 

Gurock primarily stores Data about Gurock’s customers and Data about webinars attendees, if applicable, in Europe. To facilitate Gurock’s global operations with its parent company, Idera, Inc., and its affiliated companies, Gurock may transfer and access such information from around the world, including form other countries in which Gurock has operations. A list of Gurock’s parent company and affiliated companies global offices is available at <http://www.ideracorp.com/contactus>. This Privacy Statement shall apply even if the Gurock transfers Data about Gurock customers or Data about attendees to other countries.

Gurock may retain your information for a period of time consistent with the original business purpose of collection. For example, we may retain your information during the time in which you have an account to use our Website or Services and for a reasonable period of time afterward. We may also retain your information during the period of time needed for Gurock to pursue our legitim business interest, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

You may request to review, correct, delete or otherwise modify any of the personal information that you have previously provided to us through Gurock Website and Services. If you have registered for an account with Gurock, you may generally update your user settings, profile, organization’s settings or event registration by logging into the applicable website or Services with your username and password and editing your settings or profile. For other requests to access, correct, modify or delete your Data, please email [compliance@gurock.io](mailto:%20compliance@gurock.io) and we will assist you. Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be addresses within a reasonable timeframe.

You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of Gurock’s marketing emails. Additionally, you may unsubscribe by contacting us at any time using the form on our GDPR page here. 

Gurock reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement from time to time. Gurock will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Statement through Gurock Website at least thirty (30) days prior to the change taking effect.

Questions about this Privacy Statement or the information practices of Gurock Website and Services should be directed to our privacy team by filling out this form or by emailing us at [compliance@gurock.io](mailto:%20compliance@gurock.io) or by mailing us at: 

Gurock Software GmbH  
Attn: Legal Department  
Südliche Ringstraße 175  
63225 Langen, Germany  

This website uses the Google AdWords and its remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven't completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. 

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone's past visits to the Gurock Software website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google's privacy policy. If you would like to opt out of Google cookie based advertising, please visit Google's [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

We use Google Analytics to improve the content of our website. Google Germany requires us to mention the following paragraph, intended for German visitors to learn more about how Google Analytics processes the collected data. 

    Diese Website benutzt Google Analytics, einen Webanalysedienst der Google Inc. 
    ("Google"). Google Analytics verwendet sog. "Cookies", Textdateien, die auf 
    Ihrem Computer gespeichert werden und die eine Analyse der Benutzung der 
    Website durch Sie ermöglichen. Die durch den Cookie erzeugten Informationen 
    über Ihre Benutzung dieser Website (einschließlich Ihrer IP-Adresse) wird 
    an einen Server von Google in den USA übertragen und dort gespeichert. 
    Google wird diese Informationen benutzen, um Ihre Nutzung der Website 
    auszuwerten, um Reports über die Websiteaktivitäten für die Websitebetreiber 
    zusammenzustellen und um weitere mit der Websitenutzung und der Internetnutzung 
    verbundene Dienstleistungen zu erbringen. Auch wird Google diese Informationen 
    gegebenenfalls an Dritte übertragen, sofern dies gesetzlich vorgeschrieben oder 
    soweit Dritte diese Daten im Auftrag von Google verarbeiten. Google wird in 
    keinem Fall Ihre IP-Adresse mit anderen Daten von Google in Verbindung bringen. 
    Sie können die Installation der Cookies durch eine entsprechende Einstellung 
    Ihrer Browser Software verhindern; wir weisen Sie jedoch darauf hin, dass Sie in 
    diesem Fall gegebenenfalls nicht sämtliche Funktionen dieser Website 
    vollumfänglich nutzen können. Durch die Nutzung dieser Website erklären Sie sich 
    mit der Bearbeitung der über Sie erhobenen Daten durch Google in der zuvor 
    beschriebenen Art und Weise und zu dem zuvor benannten Zweck einverstanden.
